A Guide to the Robert Young Clay Papers, 1789-2010 (bulk 1920-2007)
Library of Virginia
- Series III. Speech Files, 1974-2005., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 139-148)
  - Talks, 1976. (Box 142, Folder 12)
  - Talks, 1977. (Box 142, Folder 13)
  - National Institute of Genealogical Research, 11-29 July 1977. (Box 142, Folder 14)
  - Talks, 1978. (Box 143, Folder 1-2)
  - Talks, 1979. (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Talks, 1980. (Box 143, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Genealogical Resources, Detroit, 19 April 1980. (Box 143, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Land Office by Daphne Gentry, Virginia Genealogical Society, 1980. (Box 143, Folder 6)
  - Talks, 1981. (Box 143, Folder 7)
  - National Confederation of Kentucky and the Filson Club, 13 June 1981. (Box 143, Folder 8)
  - Talks, 1982. (Box 143, Folder 9)
  - Colonial Dames, 20 March 1982. (Box 143, Folder 10)
  - Talks, 1983. (Box 143, Folder 11)
  - St. Louis Genealogical Society, 18 June 1983. (Box 143, Folder 12)
  - Talks, 1984. (Box 143, Folder 13)
  - Fairfax Genealogical Society, 17 March 1984. (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - Tennessee Valley Genealogical Society, Huntsville AL, 14 April 1984. (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - National Genealogical Society, San Francisco, 24-26 May 1984. (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Southern Genealogists' Exchange Society, Jacksonville FL, 19-20 October 1984. (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Talks, 1984-1985. (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Talks, 1985. (Box 144, Folder 6)
  - Central Florida Genealogical Society, 23 February 1985. (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - Richmond-Stonewall Jackson Chapter UDC, 20 March 1985. (Box 144, Folder 8)
  - Nebraska State Genealogical Society, 3-4 May 1985. (Box 144, Folder 9)
  - Ohio Genealogical Society, 17-18 May 1985. (Box 144, Folder 10)
  - Alabama Genealogical Society, 25 May 1985. (Box 144, Folder 11)
  - Mid-West Tennessee Genealogical Society, 21 September 1985. (Box 144, Folder 12)
  - Culpeper Minutemen Chapter, NSDAR, 2 November 1985. (Box 144, Folder 13)
  - Three Arts Club, Blackstone, 13 November 1985. (Box 144, Folder 14)
  - Virginia State Library Staff, 13 December 1985. (Box 144, Folder 15)
  - Talks, 1986. (Box 144, Folder 16)
  - Jacksonville Genealogical Society, 1986. (Box 144, Folder 17)
  - GRIVA, 28 January 1986. (Box 144, Folder 18)
  - Richmond Relic Hunters, 4 March 1986. (Box 144, Folder 19)
  - Brevard Genealogical Society, 8 March 1986. (Box 144, Folder 20)
  - Greenwood, MS, 22 March 1986. (Box 144, Folder 21)
  - Washington, DC, 12 April 1986. (Box 144, Folder 22)
  - Free University for Senior Citizens, 18 April 1986. (Box 144, Folder 23)
  - Palatines to America, Morgantown, WV, 19-21 June1986. (Box 144, Folder 24)
  - Institute of Middle Atlantic Genealogy and History, 20 July 1986. (Box 144, Folder 25)
  - Clarksville, IN, 1-2 August 1986. (Box 144, Folder 26)
  - Kentucky Genealogical Society, 9 August 1986. (Box 144, Folder 27)
  - Augusta (SC) Genealogical Society, 2-3 October 1986. (Box 144, Folder 28)
  - Talks, 1987. (Box 144, Folder 29)
  - Genealogical Research Institute of Virginia, 6 June 1987. (Box 144, Folder 30)
  - Talks, 1988. (Box 144, Folder 31)
  - Talks, 1991. (Box 145, Folder 1-2)
  - North Carolina Genealogical Society, Raleigh, 26 October 1991. (Box 145, Folder 3)
  - Talks, 1992. (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - Jackson County (MO) Genealogical Society, 16 May 1992. (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - Botetourt County Historical Society, 27 June 1992. (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Palatines to America, Virginia Chapter, 12 September 1992. (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - New Hanover Genealogical Society, Wilmington, 15 September 1992. (Box 145, Folder 8)
  - Arkansas Genealogical Society, 30 October 1992. (Box 145, Folder 9)
  - Talks, 1993. (Box 145, Folder 10)
  - Talks, 1993-1995. (Box 145, Folder 11)
  - Heart of America Genealogical Society, Kansas City, 13 February 1993. (Box 145, Folder 12)
  - Chancellor Wythe Chapter, DAR, 10 April 1993. (Box 145, Folder 13)
  - Friends of the Archives - Using Land Office Records, 14 May 1993. (Box 145, Folder 14)
  - Owsley Family Historical Society, 14 May 1993. (Box 145, Folder 15)
  - National Genealogical Society, Baltimore, 2-5 June 1993. (Box 145, Folder 16)
  - Rose Family Association, 11-June 1993. (Box 146, Folder 1)
  - West Central Kentucky Family Research Association, Owensboro, 25 September 1993. (Box 146, Folder 2)
  - Goochland County Historical Society, 1 May 1994. (Box 146, Folder 3)
  - Conceptions and Misconceptions in Using Archival Records, 6 May 1994. (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - Genealogical Research Institute of Virginia, 24 May 1994. (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - National Genealogical Society, Houston, 1-4 June 1994. (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - Germanna Seminar, 16 July 1994. (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - Chesterfield County Historical Society, 24 July 1994. (Box 146, Folder 8)
  - Federation of Genealogical Societies, Richmond, 9-16 October 1994. (Box 146, Folder 9)
  - Colonial Dames, Wilton, 10 November 1994. (Box 146, Folder 10)
  - Talks, 1995-1996. (Box 146, Folder 11)
  - Jamestowne Society, Williamsburg, 6 May 1995. (Box 146, Folder 12)
  - Fort Worth Genealogical Society, 27 April 1996. (Box 146, Folder 13)
  - Society of the Descendants of Francis Epes I, 4 May 1996. (Box 146, Folder 14)
  - National Genealogical Society, Nashville 11 May 1996. (Box 146, Folder 15)
  - South Carolina Genealogical Society, Columbia, 13 July 1996. (Box 146, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Institute for Genealogical Research, 6-9 August 1996. (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - An Introduction to Virginia's Local Records, Augusta, GA, August 1996. (Box 147, Folder 2)
  - Why Genealogist's Fail, Augusta, GA, August 1996. (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Augusta (GA) Genalogical Society, 24 August 1996. (Box 147, Folder 4)
  - Tri-State Genealogical Society, Evansville, IN, 19 October 1996. (Box 147, Folder 5)
  - Talks, 1997. (Box 147, Folder 6)
  - Virginia County Records, Cocoa, FL, 23 February 1997. (Box 147, Folder 7)
  - Church Records, Cocoa, FL, 22 February 1997. (Box 147, Folder 8)
  - Virginia State and Colonial Records, Cocoa, FL, 22 February 1997. (Box 147, Folder 9)
  - Things Nobody Ever Tells Us, Cocoa, FL, 22 February 1997. (Box 147, Folder 10)
  - Washington Family Association, 2 May 1997. (Box 147, Folder 11)
  - Ozarks Genealogical Society, 27-28 September 1997. (Box 147, Folder 12)
  - Talks, 1999. (Box 147, Folder 13)
  - Southern Genealogists' Exchange Society, Jacksonville, FL, 24-25 September 1999. (Box 147, Folder 14)
  - Cobb County Genealogical Society Seminar, 18 March 2000. (Box 147, Folder 15)
  - Fairfax Genealogical Society, 18 March 2000. (Box 147, Folder 16)
  - Commonwealth Chapter, DAR, 28 April 2000. (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - Montgomery County TX Genealogical Society, 24 June 2000. (Box 148, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Institute of Genealogical Research, 6-10 August 2000. (Box 148, Folder 3)
  - Society of Colonial Wars, 8 November 2000. (Box 148, Folder 4)
  - Tri-Club Woman's Club, 4 January 2001. (Box 148, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax Genealogical Society Spring Conference, 31 March 2001. (Box 148, Folder 6)
  - San Antonio Genealogical Society, 27 October 2001. (Box 148, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Genealogical Society 9-13 June 2002. (Box 148, Folder 8)
  - Archives Week, 2002. (Box 148, Folder 9)
  - FGS and Florida State Genealogical Society, 3-6 September 2003. (Box 148, Folder 10)
  - Leftwich Historical Association, 17-18 October 2003. (Box 148, Folder 11)
  - Tennessee Genealogical Society, Fall 2003. (Box 148, Folder 12)
  - Mississippi Genealogical Society, 15 January 2005. (Box 148, Folder 13-15)
  - Talks, n.d. (Box 148, Folder 16)
  - South Carolina Genealogical Society. (Box 148, Folder 17)
- Series IV. Smith County, TN Soldiers' Pension Files., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 149-154)
  The Smith County, TN Soldiers' Pension Files series contains copies of War of 1812 pension application files Clay obtained from the National Archives, which he abstracted and prepared for publication in the Smith County Historical and Genealogical Quarterly. The first appeared in the Winter 1997 issue. The files are arranged alphabetically by soldier's name.
  - Muster Rolls. (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - NARA - Forms. (Box 149, Folder 2)
  - NARA, 19 March 1988. (Box 149, Folder 3)
  - Smith County, TN Soldiers. (Box 149, Folder 4-11)
  - Smith County, TN Soldiers Lists and Searches. (Box 149, Folder 12)
  - Smith County Historical and Genealogical Society. (Box 150, Folder 1)
  - Adams, John. (Box 150, Folder 2)
  - Adcock, John. (Box 150, Folder 3)
  - Alexander, William. (Box 150, Folder 4-5)
  - Allen, Duke. (Box 150, Folder 6)
  - Alves, Ashley. (Box 150, Folder 7)
  - Armistead, Thaddeus. (Box 150, Folder 8)
  - Armstrong, John. (Box 150, Folder 9)
  - Baines, Samuel. (Box 150, Folder 10)
  - Ballard, John. (Box 150, Folder 11)
  - Barnes, James. (Box 150, Folder 12)
  - Beasley, Isham. (Box 150, Folder 13)
  - Beasley, Major A.. (Box 150, Folder 14)
  - Bethel, Sampson. (Box 150, Folder 15)
  - Boston, George. (Box 150, Folder 16)
  - Bradley, Isaac. (Box 150, Folder 17)
  - Bradley, James. (Box 151, Folder 1)
  - Bradley, John. (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - Brown, James. (Box 151, Folder 3)
  - Burford, David. (Box 151, Folder 4)
  - Burford, Robert A.. (Box 151, Folder 5)
  - Burford, William G.. (Box 151, Folder 6)
  - Carr, James. (Box 151, Folder 7)
  - Carter, Charles. (Box 151, Folder 8)
  - Carter, William. (Box 151, Folder 9)
  - Claiborne, John. (Box 151, Folder 10)
  - Coley, Francis. (Box 151, Folder 11)
  - Cooper, Meredith. (Box 151, Folder 12)
  - Coram, Robert. (Box 151, Folder 13)
  - Cornwell, William G.. (Box 151, Folder 14)
  - Cunningham, William. (Box 151, Folder 15)
  - Day, Philip. (Box 151, Folder 16)
  - Debow, Solomon. (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Dennie, William. (Box 152, Folder 2)
  - Dickerson, Olive. (Box 152, Folder 3)
  - Dickson, William. (Box 152, Folder 4)
  - Doss, James A.. (Box 152, Folder 5)
  - Duncan, Elijah. (Box 152, Folder 6)
  - Evans, William D.. (Box 152, Folder 7)
  - Faire, Jonathan. (Box 152, Folder 8)
  - Fuller, Isham. (Box 152, Folder 9)
  - Gammon, Jeremiah. (Box 152, Folder 10)
  - Gammon, Levi. (Box 152, Folder 11)
  - Gent, Jesse. (Box 152, Folder 12)
  - Gill, Jesse. (Box 152, Folder 13)
  - Gillehan, Clemons (Clement). (Box 152, Folder 14)
  - Goldman, Donoho. (Box 152, Folder 15)
  - Goodner, James. (Box 152, Folder 16)
  - Gregory, Wiliam. (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Hale, Cage. (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - Harper, Josiah. (Box 153, Folder 3)
  - Harvey, John. (Box 153, Folder 4)
  - Herod, Peter. (Box 153, Folder 5)
  - Hinds, John. (Box 153, Folder 6)
  - King, William. (Box 153, Folder 7)
  - Maiden, Lawrence. (Box 153, Folder 8)
  - Meador, Isham. (Box 153, Folder 9)
  - Meador, Joel. (Box 153, Folder 10)
  - Meador, Jonas. (Box 153, Folder 11)
  - Moore, William. (Box 153, Folder 12)
  - Parkhurst, Elijah. (Box 153, Folder 13)
  - Paschal, John H.. (Box 153, Folder 14)
  - Paschal, John Jr.. (Box 153, Folder 15)
  - Patterson, Hugh K.. (Box 153, Folder 16)
  - Price, Jesse. (Box 153, Folder 17)
  - Reece, John S.. (Box 153, Folder 18)
  - Robinson, Spearman. (Box 153, Folder 19)
  - Roper, John Y.. (Box 153, Folder 20)
  - Saunders, Jordan. (Box 154, Folder 1)
  - Scudder, Matthias. (Box 154, Folder 2)
  - See, William. (Box 154, Folder 3)
  - Sims, Micajah. (Box 154, Folder 4)
  - Tyree, William. (Box 154, Folder 5)
  - Wright, Romulus C.. (Box 154, Folder 6)
  - Young, Cyrus. (Box 154, Folder 7)
  - Young, William. (Box 169, Folder 18)
- Series V. Artwork., Extent: 8 boxes. (Box 155-162)
  The Artwork series includes materials related to Clay's interest in heraldic art, landscape painting, and quilting. There are sales account books, correspondence with clients concerning orders, progress, and payment for work, sketchbooks, coats of arms sketches by Clay arranged alphabetically by surname, and photographs of his final work. There are also announcements, brochures and flyers, design ideas, and articles related to Clay's artistic pursuits.
  - Account Book - Coats of Arms Sales, 1960-2003. (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Aiken, Bobbie. (Box 155, Folder 2)
  - Alden, Mrs. Scott. (Box 155, Folder 3)
  - Allen, Nancy Quarles. (Box 155, Folder 4)
  - Announcements, Brochures, Flyers. (Box 155, Folder 5)
  - Antiques (September 1998). (Box 169, Folder 2)
  - Armstrong, John Bailey. (Box 155, Folder 6)
  - "Arts in the Park: A Story". (Box 155, Folder 7)
  - Artwork (Other Artists). (Box 169, Folder 3)
  - Clay - Heraldry. (Box 155, Folder 8)
  - Coats of Arms. (Box 170, Folder 6)
  - Coats of Arms - Articles. (Box 155, Folder 9-10)
  - Coats of Arms - Correspondence. (Box 155, Folder 11-14)
  - Coats of Arms - Sales. (Box 156, Folder 1-3)
  - Coats of Arms - Sales (Index Cards). (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - Coats of Arms - Sketches (A-J). (Box 156, Folder 5-14)
  - Coats of Arms - Sketches (K-Z). (Box 157, Folder 1-18)
  - Coats of Arms - Virginia Cavalcade, 1959. (Box 157, Folder 19)
  - Coats of Arms - Xerox Copies. (Box 157, Folder 20)
  - County Seals. (Box 157, Folder 21)
  - Crossroads Art Center. (Box 157, Folder 22)
  - Dennstedt, Alberta. (Box 157, Folder 23)
  - Designs. (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Designs - Drawings. (Box 158, Folder 2)
  - Designs - Furniture and Gardens. (Box 158, Folder 3)
  - Designs - Lettering. (Box 158, Folder 4)
  - Designs - Quilts. (Box 158, Folder 5-8)
  - Dinwiddie County Seal. (Box 158, Folder 9)
  - Emily Whaley Studio. (Box 158, Folder 10)
  - Frix, Grace Jones. (Box 158, Folder 11)
  - Heraldic Gravestones. (Box 158, Folder 12)
  - Heraldic Illustrations. (Box 158, Folder 13)
  - Heraldic Sketches. (Box 158, Folder 14)
  - Heraldry. (Box 159, Folder 1)
  - Illustrated Calendar, 2001. (Box 166)
  - Introduction to Heraldry. (Box 159, Folder 2)
  - Jones, Lucy. (Box 159, Folder 3)
  - Kannady, Mrs. Roy E. (Arms). (Box 159, Folder 4)
  - Kennedy, Sally P.. (Box 159, Folder 5)
  - Kirby, Lewis. (Box 159, Folder 6)
  - Lakeshore Quilters Guild - "Viewers Choice Award" - Quilt Made for Natalie and Fred Blumberg by RYC, 1989. (Box 159, Folder 7)
  - "Landscape: Real and Remembered" Exhibit, Main Art Gallery, 2007. (Box 159, Folder 8)
  - Lettering. (Box 159, Folder 9)
  - Painting - Sales. (Box 159, Folder 10-11)
  - Picture Frames. (Box 159, Folder 12)
  - Polish Heraldry. (Box 159, Folder 13)
  - Presley, Caren. (Box 159, Folder 14)
  - Raleigh - Coat of Arms (John Neville Article). (Box 159, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook (Coats of Arms Clippings). (Box 166)
  - Seals. (Box 159, Folder 16)
  - Seals (Heraldic). (Box 159, Folder 17)
  - Shaw-Gallant, Catherine. (Box 159, Folder 18)
  - Sketchbook. (Box 171, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbooks. (Box 159, Folder 19-20)
  - Smith County Seals. (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Spivey, Wallace R.. (Box 160, Folder 2)
  - Stewart, Jack. (Box 160, Folder 3)
  - Sullivant, Sarah. (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Heraldry. (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - Work, Late 1992-1993. (Box 160, Folder 6-8)
  - Work, 1994-1996. (Box 160, Folder 9-12)
  - Work, 1998-1999. (Box 160, Folder 13-17)
  - Work, 2002-2003. (Box 161, Folder 1-6)
  - Work, n.d.. (Box 161, Folder 7-14)
  - Work, n.d.. (Box 162, Folder 1-13)
- Oversize Materials., Extent: 1 oversize folder. (Folder 1)